Never never never surrender
Darkest Hour is a drama, history film directed by Joe Wright.
In May 1940, the fate of World War II hangs on Winston Churchill, who must decide whether to negotiate
with Adolf Hitler or fight on knowing that it could mean the end of the British Empire.
Winston Churchill, played by Gary Oldman.
Viscount Halifax, played by Stephen Dillane.
Elizabeth Layton, played by Lily James.
Neville Chamberlain, played by Ronald Pickup.
King George VI, played by Ben Mendelsohn.
Clemmie, played by Kristin Scott Thomas.
Darkest Hour is a 2017 British biographical war drama film
directed by Joe Wright and written by Anthony McCarten.
It stars Gary Oldman as Winston Churchill, in his early days as Prime Minister of the
United Kingdom during the Second World War and the May 1940 war cabinet crisis.
The cast also includes Kristin Scott Thomas as Clementine Churchill, Lily James as Elizabeth Layton, Stephen
Dillane as Viscount Halifax, Ronald Pickup as Neville Chamberlain, and Ben Mendelsohn as King George VI.
The title of the film refers to a description of the early
days of the war, widely attributed to Churchill.
Darkest Hour had its world premiere at the 44th
Telluride Film Festival on 1 September 2017.
It began a limited release in the US on 22 November 2017, followed by a wide
release on 22 December, and was released on 12 January 2018 in the UK.
The film grossed $150 million worldwide and received positive reviews from
critics, who deemed Oldman's performance one of the best of his career.
Darkest Hour received several accolades, including Best Actor for Oldman at the
Academy Awards, the BAFTAs, the Golden Globes, and the SAG Awards.
The film explores themes of world war ii, biography, based on
true story, london underground, british politics.
The tone is emotional.